Norman Corwin Papers
Norman Corwin Papers
- Productions of Corwin
  - Radio programs, individual
    - One World Flight, 1947
      - Recording, No. 5 U.S.S.R., work cuts
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union Parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0029; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. "Khatc" presumably refers to Khatchaturian. Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - Ex-soldier II; 2 - Sura sings; 3 - Sura (hopes); 4 - Sura (re work); 5 - Khatca (re 2 composers); 6 - Khatc (re piano); 7 - Khatc (re curfew); Side 2 (Part 4): Moscow New Editor
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union Parts 5 and 6 [disc 3 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0030; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. "Solslovsky" possibly a misspelling of David Zoslovsky. "Khatc" presumably refers to Khatchaturian. Side 1 has 11 tracks and 10 titles, as one of the track has a grease pen marking on it. Side 1 (Part 5): 1 - Khatc. (re art); 2 - Khatc. (war); 3 - Khatc. (spirit); 4 - Khatc. (housing); 5 - Metro (smoking); 6 - Metro (spl train); 7 - Forum (Christ); 8 - Forum (re war); 9 - Forum (Unamerican) [sic.]; 10 - Forum (re Spain); Side 2 (Part 6): 1 - Forum (re praise); 2 - Forum (Corwin); 3 - Banquet (re war, peace); 4 - Banquet (re ties); 5 - Solslovsky I; 6 - Solslovsky II
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union Parts 7 and 8 [disc 4 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0031; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. "Solslovsky" possibly a misspelling of David Zoslovsky. The name of Mi︠a︡skovskiĭ is omitted on the record's label, it is handwritten as Miaskovsky on the disk. Side 1 has 7 tracks and 6 titles, one track has a grease pen marking on it. Side 2 has 7 tracks while the label indicates 8 tracks, unclear if track 8 Miaskovsky I appears on the record. Side 1 (Part 7): 1 - Solslovsky III (re Atkinson); 2 - Solslovsky IV (iron curtain); 3 - Solslovsky V (dillo); 4 - Solslovsky VI (13 by Corwin); 5 - Solslovsky (Capitalist); 6 - Solslovsky (peace); Side 2 (Part 8): 1 - Solslovsky (newspapers); 2 - Prokofiev I; 3 - Prokofiev II; 4 - Prokofiev III; 5 - Prokofiev IV; 6 - Prokofiev V; 7 - Prokofiev VI; 8 - Miaskovsky I
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union Parts 9 and 10 [disc 5 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0032; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. The name of Mi︠a︡skovskiĭ is omitted on the record's label, it is handwritten as Miaskovksy on the disk. Side 1 has 10 tracks while the label indicates 9 tracks, unclear if track 8 - Miaskovsky I, from the record corwin_0031 is on the recording. Side 1 (Part 9): 1 - Miaskovksy II; 2 - Miaskovksy III; 3 - Miaskovksy IV; 4 - Miaskovksy V; 5 - Miaskovksy VI; 6 - Lamm; 7 - Kapitza I; 8 - Kapitza II; 9 - Kapitza III; Side 2 (Part 10): 1 - Kapitza IV; 2 - [Sergei] Eisenstein I; 3 - Eisenstein II; 4 - Eisenstein III; 5 - Eisenstein IV; 6 - Eisenstein V; 7 - Eisenstein VI
        - One World Flight: The Soviet Union [disc 6 of 6], 02/11/1947; corwin_0033; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 1: Khatchaturian at Home; Side 2: Khachaturian at Home
      - Recording, No. 6 Czechoslovakia
        Includes interviews with President Eduard Benes, miners, a lawyer, a professor, resident writers at Writers' Syndicate palace in Dobris.
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 02/18/1947; corwin_0011; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 02/18/1947; corwin_0012; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 6 Czechoslovakia, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes excerpts from interview with President Eduard Benes, miners, lawyers, a professor, resident writers at a Syndicate Palace in Dobris.
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia [disc 1 of 5], 02/18/1947; corwin_0034; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 2 has 5 tracks and 4 titles; one of the tracks has grease pen marking on it. Side 1: 6-57; 6-58; 6-59; 6-48; 6-61; 6-62; 6-63; 6-65; Side 2: 6-66; 6-67; 6-68; 6-69
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia [disc 2 of 5], 02/18/1947; corwin_0035; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 1: 6-18; 6-19; 6-20; 6-22; 6-23; 6-24; 6-25; 6-26; Side 2: 6-1; 6-5; 6-9; 6-10; 6-12; 6-15; 6-16; 6-17
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia [disc 3 of 5], 02/18/1947; corwin_0036; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 2 has six tracks on the disc. First track not digitized; has an "X" on it in red grease pen. Side 1: 6-4; 6-8; 6-13; 6-30; 6-33; 6-34; Side 2: 6-31; 6-32; 6-38; 6-21; 6-7
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia [disc 4 of 5], 02/18/1947; corwin_0037; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Side 1: 6-37; 6-40; 6-41; 6-43; 6-45; Side 2: 6-46; 6-47A; 6-47B; 6-49; 6-50; 6-51; 6-52; 6-53; 6-54; 6-55 rev; 6-56
        - One World Flight: Czechoslovakia [disc 5 of 5], 02/18/1947; corwin_0038; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Side 1: 6-70; 6-71; 6-72; 6-73
      - Recording, No. 7 Italy
        Street interviews in Rome and village of Lanuvio in the Albani mountains. Includes statements by Prime Minister Alcide DeGaspari, Ugo La Malfa of the Action Party, Palmiro Tagliatti, Communist leader, Sergio Amidei, screenwriter who wrote the famous movie Open City, etc. Disk labeled Set "A"
        - One World Flight: Italy Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 02/25/1947; corwin_0013; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Italy Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 02/25/1947; corwin_0014; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 7 Italy, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes street interviews in Rome and village of Lanuvio, meetings between Corwin and Prime Minister Alcide DeGasperi, Sergio Amidei, Palmiro Tagliatti, Ugo La Malfa, and others
        - One World Flight: Italy [disc 1 of 4], 02/25/1947; corwin_0079; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the label next to each work cut there is a handwritten title. For further reference see the digital image of the record's label. On Side 1 label the work cuts 7-12, 7-13, and 7-14 are crossed off. Side 1: 7-1; 7-2; 7-3 Work; 7-4; 7-5; 7-6; 7-7 We helped; 7-8; 7-9; 7-10; 7-11 We wait 2 help; Side 2: 7-18; 7-16; 7-15; 7-19; 7-21; 7-22; 7-23; 7-24 We await help; 7-25; 7-26 Am must respect; 7-27 Settle with war; 7-28 Wave of banditry
        - One World Flight: Italy [disc 2 of 4], 02/25/1947; corwin_0080; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the label next to each work cut there is a handwritten title. For further reference see the digital image of the record's label. Side 1: 7-29; 7-30; 7-31 My ma is American; 7-32; 7-33; 7-34; 7-35; 7-36; 7-38 Amidei; 7-39; 7-40 De Gasperi; Side 2: 7-41 Tagliatti; 7-43; 7-44; 7-45; 7-47; 7-48; 7-50; 7-51; 7-52; 7-53; 7-54
        - One World Flight: Italy [disc 3 of 4], 02/25/1947; corwin_0081; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the label next to each work cut there is a handwritten title. For further reference see the digital image of the record's label. Side 1: 7-55; 7-57; 7-58 La Malfa; 7-59 La Malfa; 7-61; 7-62; 7-63; 7-65 La Malfa; 7-66; 7-67; 7-68; Side 2: 7-69 La Malfa; 7-71 La Malfa; 7-72 De Gasperi; 7-73; 7-74; 7-75; 7-76; 7-77; 7-79; 7 -80 Lanuvio; 7 [unreadable]
        - One World Flight: Italy [disc 4 of 4], 02/25/1947; corwin_0082; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the label next to each work cut there is a handwritten title. For further reference see the digital image of the record's label. 7-82 Bread + tomato, Lanuvio; 7-83 Lanuvio; 7-84; Lanuvio; 7-85 Lanuvio; 7- 86 Lanuvio; 7- 87; 7- 88; 7-89
      - Recording, No. 8 Egypt and India
        Includes excerpts of an interview with Pandit Nehru in the home of his nephew; people on the streets of Cairo; etc. George Polk, CBS correspondent who was assassinated in Greece a year or so later, served as Corwin's interpreter in many of the Egyptian interviews, and his voice is heard frequently. The visit to India was at the time of the terrible religious riots between Hindus and Moslems, in which thousands were slain.
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 03/04/1947; corwin_0015; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 03/04/1947; corwin_0016; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 8 Egypt and India, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes excerpts of an interview with Pandit Nehru in New Delhi (of which relatively little was actually used on the broadcast) and a number of interviews in Cairo; in the latter, George Polk, CBS correspondent who was assassinated in Salonika the following year, served as interpreter, and his voice is heard frequently.
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India Parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 4], 03/04/1947; corwin_0071; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. On labels, titles of work cuts are handwritten in black and red pen next to each other. Some of the titles in black pen differ from the titles in red pen. Titles in red pen are given here in brackets. Side two has 9 titles and 10 tracks. It is unclear what is the title of track 10. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 8-1; 2 - 8-2; 3 - 8-3; 4 - 8-4; 5 - 8-5; 6 - 8-6; 7 - 8-7; 8 - 8-8; 9 - 8-10 (8); 10 - 8-11 (a?); Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 8-13 (9A); 2 - 8-14 (9B); 3 - 8-16 (10); 4 - 8-17 (11); 5 - 8-18 (12); 6 - 8-19 (13a); 7 - 8-20 (14a); 8 - 8-23 (14b); 9 -8-25 (15)
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India Parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 4], 03/04/1947; corwin_0072; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. On labels, titles of work cuts are handwritten in black and red pen next to each other. Some of the titles in black pen differ from the titles in red pen. Titles in red pen are given here in brackets. Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - 8-26-27 (horns); 2 - 8-29 (16); 3 - 8-30 (17); 4 - 8-32 (18); 5 - 8-42 (20); 6 - 8-43 (21); 7 - 8-31 (19); 8 - 8-45 (22A); 9 - 8-47 (23); 10 - 8-48 (24); 11 - 8-11 Rev (1a?); 12 - 8-20 Rev (13); Side 2 (Part 4): 1 - 8-33 (Salama); 2 - 8-34 (crowd); 3 - 8-35 (crowd); 4 - 8-36; 5 - 8-37; 6 - 8-38; 7 - 8-40A; 8 - 8-40B
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India Parts 5 and 6 [disc 3 of 4], 03/04/1947; corwin_0073; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. corwin_0074, (12" disc) is in the same sleeve. Side 1 (Part 5): Nehru 1 - 8-49; 2 - 8-50; 3 - 8-51; 4 - 8-52; 5 - 8-53; 6 - 8-54; Side 2 (Part 6): Nehru 1 - 8-55; 2 - 8-56; 3 - 8-58
        - One World Flight: Egypt and India [disc 4 of 4], 03/04/1947; corwin_0074; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Only existing copy of work cuts. corwin_0073 is in same sleeve. Side 1: 8-57
      - Recording, No. 9 China
        This constitutes one of the last aural reports to come from within China before it fell to the Communists. Because Willkie was well remembered in China, from his visit in 1942, the One World mission was received with great warmth. Includes material recorded in Nanking, Shanghai and Peiping; interviews with Mayor Wu of Shanghai; Minister of Information Peng Hsueh Pei; Dr. H. H. Kung, who claimed descent from Confucius; Dr. Sun Fo, son of China's first president, Sun Yat Sen; General Chou En-Lai, since very high in the Peking government; Walter Robertson, U.S. Commissioner at Executive Headquarters in Peiping (later No. 1 U.S. representative in Korea); General Chang Kai-Ming of the Nationalists; General Yeh Chien-Ying, Communist; writers, artists, etc.
        - One World Flight: China Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 03/11/1947; corwin_0017; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: China Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 03/11/1947; corwin_0018; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 9 China, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes excerpts from interviews with Chou En Lai; Mayor of Shanghai; Mayor of Nanking; Hu Shih; American, National and Communist Commissioners at Executive Headquarters in Peiping; and many others
        - One World Flight: China Parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0083; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the label next to some of the work cuts there is a handwritten title. For further reference see the digital image of the record's label. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 9-1; 2 - 9-2; 3 - 9-4; 4 - 9-5; 5 - 9-6; 6 - 9-7; 7 - 9-8; 8 - 9-9; 9 - 9-10; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 9-11 Vendor; 2 - 9-12 Dr. Peng; 3 - 9-13 Dr. Peng; 4 - 9-14; 5 - 9-15
        - One World Flight: China Parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0084; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. Side 1 has 9 tracks and 7 titles, as two of the tracks have a grease pen on them. Side 2 has 12 tracks and 11 titles, one track has a grease pen on it. Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - 9-3; 2 - 9-15B; 3 - 9-16A; 4 - 9-16B; 5 - 9-18; 6 - 9-19; 7 - 9-20; Side 2 (Part 4): 1 - 9-21; 2 - 9-22; 3 - 9-23A; 4 - 9-23B; 5 - 9-23C; 6 - 9-25A; 7 - 9-25B; 8 - 9-27A; 9 - 9-27B; 10 - 9-29A; 11 - 9-29B
        - One World Flight: China Parts 5 and 6 [disc 3 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0085; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. Side 1 indicates 14 titles (14 - 9-43), but the disc only has 13 bands. It is unclear what the 14th title refers to. Side 1: 1 - 9-31A; 2 - 9-31B; 3 - 9-33A; 4 - 9-33B; 5 - 9-33C; 6 - 9-35A; 7 - 9-35B; 8 - 9-37; 9 - 9-38; 10 - 9-39A; 11 - 9-39B; 12 - 9-41; 13 - 9-42; 14 - 9-43; Side 2 (Part 6): 1 - 9-44; 2 - 9-45; 3 - 9-46; 4 - 9-47; 5 - 9-48; 6 - 9-49; 7 - 9-50; 8 - 9-51; 9 - 9-52; 10 - 9-53; 11 - 9-54
        - One World Flight: China Part 7 [disc 4 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0086; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. On the disc label in a red pen next to the titles is written "Gen. Yeh" Part 7: 1 - 9-55; 2 - 9-56; 3 - 9-57; 4 - 9-58; 5 - 9-59; 6 - 9-60
        - One World Flight: China [disc 5 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0087; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. Side 1: 1 - 9-61 (Mayor Wu); 2 - 9-62 (Che Li Lo); 3 - 9-63 (Mr. Chu); 4 - 9-64 (actress [most likely to be Miss Chang]); 5 - 9-65 (Mei Lan Fang); 6 - 9-66 (Mr. Fung); 7 - 9-67 (Gen Wu); 8 - 9-68 (Dr. Peng); 9 - 9-69 (Mr. Hu); 10 -9-70 (Mr. Wu No 2); 11 - 9-71 (Dr. Chu); 12 - 9-72 (Dr. Kung); 13 - 9-73 (Dr. Wang); 14 - 9-74 (Dr. Chin); 15 9-75 (Mayor Ma); Side 2: 1 - 9-76A; 2 - 9-76B
        - One World Flight: China [disc 6 of 6], 03/11/1947; corwin_0088; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only existing copy of work cuts. 1 - 9-77 Bells; 2 - 9-78A Siren; 3 - 9-78B Siren; 4 - 9-79 Traffic on Bond
      - Address over radio station XHMA in Shanghai, China, 09/02/1946; corwin_0287; Lacquer discs/acetates
        Address over radio station XMHA in Shanghai, China on September 2, 1946, on the eve of Corwin's departure from China for Japan, on his One World Flight journey. Corwin was invited to record an extemporaneous preface to a playing of his program "On a Note of triumph" from discs. Corwin's comments, and the playback of the program, were the principal feature of the final day of the station's existence. XMHA was operated by the United States Army, through a unit in Shanghai, and it was closed down when this unit was phased out. Text unpublished. Only existing copy.
      - Recording, No. 10 The Philippines
        Includes interviews with President Manuel Roxas, first American ambassador to the Philippines, Paul V. McNutt, people on the street, Dr. Vincente Lava, scientist, etc. There is a handwritten note on the sleeve.
        - One World Flight: The Philippines Part 1 [disc 1 of 2], 03/18/1947; corwin_0019; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: The Philippines Part 2 [disc 2 of 2], 03/18/1947; corwin_0020; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 10 The Philippines, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes interviews with President Manuel Roxas, whom Corwin visited in the Malcanan Palace; and Paul V. McNutt, first United States Ambassador to the Philippines. Also Dr. Vincente Lavam [sic] scientist, and people on the street of Manila.
        - One World Flight: Philippines Parts 1 and 2 [disc 1 of 5], 03/18/1947; corwin_0061; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 10-1; 2 - 10-2; 3 - 10-3; 4 - 10-4A; 5 - 10-4B; 6 - 10-6; 7 - 10-7 rev; 8 - 10-8; 9 - 10-9A; 10 - 10-9B; 11 - 10-11; 12 - 10-12; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 10-13; 2 - 10-14; 3 - 10-15; 4 - 10-16; 5 - 10-17; 6 - 10-18; 7 - 10-19; 8 - 10-20
        - One World Flight: Philippines Parts 3 and 4 [disc 2 of 5], 03/18/1947; corwin_0062; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - 10-21; 2 - 10-22; 3 - 10-23; 4 - 10-24; 5 - 10-25; 6 - 10-26; Side 2 (Part 4): 1 - 10-27; 2 - 10-28; 3 - 10-29; 4 - 10-30; 5 - 10-31; 6 - 10-32; 7 - 10-33; 8 - 10-34; 9 - 10-35; 10 - 10-36; 11 - 10-37
        - One World Flight: Philippines Parts 5 and 6 [disc 3 of 5], 03/18/1947; corwin_0063; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 5): 1 - 10-38; 2 - 10-39; 3 - 10-40; 4 - 10-41; Side 2 (Part 6): 1 - 10-42; 2 - 10-43
        - One World Flight: Philippines Part 7 [disc 4 of 5], 03/18/1947; corwin_0064; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only copy. Part 7: 1 - 10-44; 2 - 10-45; 3 - 10-46; 4 -10-47; 5 - 10-48; 6 - 10-49; 7 -10-50; 8 - 10-54; 9 - 10-55; 10 -10-56; 11 - 10-57
        - One World Flight: Philippines [disc 5 of 5], 03/18/1947; corwin_0065; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only copy. 10-51; 10 -52; 10-53 rev
      - Recording, No. 11 Australia
        Interview with dockhands, factory workers, factory owner, sheep herder, election workers, Premier of New South Wales J. B. McKell, later Governor General of Australia. The reception in Australia was particularly warm, since Corwin's plays had frequently been produced over the facilities of the Australia Broadcasting Commission.
        - One World Flight: Australia Part 1 [disc 1 of 3], 03/25/1947; corwin_0021; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Australia Part 2 original [disc 2 of 3], 03/25/1947; corwin_0022; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: Australia Part 2 revised [disc 3 of 3], 03/25/1947; corwin_0023; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 11 Australia, work cuts
        "Work Cuts"; disc set includes interviews with dockhands, factory workers, industrialist, sheep herder, election workers, Premier of South Wales J. B. McKell, later to become Governor General of Australia
        - One World Flight: Australia "Norman Corwin Mike Test" [disc 1 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0052; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Label on disc has different date, presumably 01/12/1947 is the date of the recording.
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 1 and 2 [disc 2 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0053; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 1): 1 - 11-1; 2 - 11-2; 3 - 11-3; 4 - 11-4; 5 - 11-5; 6 - 11-7; 7 - 11-7; 8 - 11-8; 9 - 11-9; Side 2 (Part 2): 1 - 11-10; 2 - 11-11; 3 - 11-12; 4 - 11-13; 5 - 11-14; 6 - 11-15; 7 - 11-16; 8 - 11-17; 9 - 11-18; 10 - 11-19; 11 - 11-20
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 3 and 4 [disc 3 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0054; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 3): 1 - 11-21; 2 - 11-22; 3 - 11-23; 4 - 11-24 ABCDEF; 5 - 11-24G; 6 - 11-25; 7 - 11-26; 8 - 11-27; 9 - 11-28; 10 - 11-29A; 11 - 11-29B; 12 - 11-29C; 13 - 11-30; 14 - 11-31; 15 - 11-32A; 16 - 11-32B; 17 - 11-32C; 11-32D; 11-32E; 11-32F; Side 2 (Part 4): 1 - 11-33A; 2 - 11-33B; 3 - 11-35A; 4 - 11-35B; 5 - 11-35C; 6 - 11-36A; 7 - 11-36B; 8 - 11-36C; 9 - 11-36D; 10 - 11-36E; 11 - 11-36D; 12 - 11-37A; 13- 11-37B; 14 - 11-17C
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 5 and 6 [disc 4 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0055; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 5):1 - 11-34A; 2 - 11-34B; 3 - 11-34C; 4 - 11-34D; 5 - 11-38A; 6 - 11-38B; 7 - 11-39B; 8 - 11-40; 9 -11-41A; 10 - 11-41B; 11 - 11-41C; Side 2 (Part 6): 1 - 11-42A; 2 - 11-42B; 3 - 11-43A; 4 - 11-43B; 5 - 11-43C; 6 -11-44C; 7 - 11-44D; 8 - 11-45A; 9 - 11-45B; 10 - 1145C
        - One World Flight: Australia Part 7 [disc 5 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0056; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 7): 1 - 11-45D; 2 - 11-45E; 3 -11-45F; 4 - 11-45G; 5 - 11-45H; 6 - 11-45I; 7 - 11-46A; 8 - 11-46B; 9 - 11-46C; 10 - 11-46D; 11 - 11-46E; 12 - 11-46F
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 8 and 9 [disc 6 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0057; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 8): 1 - 11-53; 2 - 11-54; 3 - 11-55; 4 - 11-44A; 5 - 11-44B; 6 - 11-47A; 7 - 11-47B; 8 - 11-47C; 9 - 11-47D; 10 - 11-47E; 11 - 11-47F; 12 - 11-47G; 13 - 11-47H; 14 - 11-47I; 15 - 11-47J; 16 - 11-47K; Side 2 (Part 9): 1 - 11-48A; 2 - 11-48B; 3 - 11-48C; 4 - 11-48D; 5 - 11-48E; 6 - 11-48F; 7 - 11-48G; 8 - 11-48H; 9 - 11-49; 10 - 11-50A; 11 - 11-50B; 12 - 11-50C
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 10 and 11 [disc 7 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0058; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 10): 1 - 11-50D; 2 - 11-50E; 3 - 11-50F; 4 - 11-50G; 5 - 11-50H; 6 - 11-50I; 7 - 11-50J; 8 - 11-50K; 9 - 11-50L; 10 - 11-50M; 11 - 11-50N; 12 - 11-50O; Side 2 (Part 11): 1 - 11-51A; 2 - 11-51B; 3 - 11-51C; 4 - 11-51D; 5 - 11-51E; 6 - 11-51F; 7 - 11-52A; 8 - 11-52B; 9 - 11-52C; 10 - 11-52D; 11 - 11-52E; 12 - 11-52F; 13 - 11-52G; 14 - 11-52H; 15 - 11-52I; 16 - 11-52J
        - One World Flight: Australia Part 12 [disc 8 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0059; Lacquer discs/acetates
          One sided disc. Only copy. Part 12: 1 - 11-56; 2 - 11-39A; 3 - 11-39B; 4 - 11-39C; 5 - 11-39D; 6 -11-39E; 7 - 11-39F
        - One World Flight: Australia Parts 13 and 14 [disc 9 of 9], 03/25/1947; corwin_0060; Lacquer discs/acetates
          Two sided disc. Only copy. Side 1 (Part 13): 1 - 11-57; 2 - 11-58; 3 - 11-60; 4 - 11-61; 5 - 11-62; 6 - 11- 63; 7 - 11-63; 8 - 11-64; Side 2 (Part 14): 1 - 11-66; 2 - 11-67; 3 - 11-68; 4 - 11-69; 5 - 11-70
      - Departure From Australia, 10/04/1946; statement by Corwin on leaving Australia for New Zealand; corwin_0351; Lacquer discs/acetates
        Statement on departure from Australia for New Zealand, in the course of Corwin's ONE WORLD FLIGHT. Dated October 4, 1946. Included in this envelope is also a memorandum from G. E. Clay of the Australian Broadcasting Commission to "Murph" which reads: "Norman Corwin (God bless him) is leaving by flying-boat on Friday morning, about six, for N.Z. You will hardly have time to get an interview, so Cotton has had a record prepared of Corwin's farewell message to Australia. This Cotton wants used, when you announce Corwin's departure in your morning session. Just as well, of course, to check that has actually left, but if you can get Paul to do this by phone...It is only 12 seconds long, so ought to be easy to work in." The statement was not worth all the trouble. in addition to being only 12 seconds long, it sounds truncated. The hour of 6 referred to was AM.
      - Recording, No. 12 New Zealand
        Includes Maori chorus, schoolchildren, Minister of Native Affairs, housewife, doctor, dentist, Prime Minister Peter Fraser, etc.
        - One World Flight: New Zealand [disc 1 of 2], 04/08/1947; corwin_0024; Lacquer discs/acetates
        - One World Flight: New Zealand [disc 2 of 2], 04/08/1947; corwin_0025; Lacquer discs/acetates
      - Recording, No. 12 New Zealand, rehearsal
        - One World Flight: Rehearsal of Program No 12, New Zealand [disc 1 of 2], 04/01/1947; corwin_0066; Lacquer discs/acetates